RESEARCH STATEMENT

My research is dedicated to addressing the multifaceted aspects of LLMs, pushing the boundaries of its capabilities, and ultimately enhancing LLMs. My areas of interest include alignment, safety, evaluation, and others. However, with recent work breaking alignment of LLMs via adversarial attacks (or otherwise), we are still yet to make strides in area alignment and safety.

EDUCATION

Ph.D, Computer Science 2021 - Present University of Maryland, College Park College Park

Advisor: Prof. Tom Goldstein

M.S, Computer Science 2021 - 2023
University of Maryland, College Park College Park

GPA: 3.87; Advisor: Prof. Tom Goldstein

B.A, Honors in Mathematics Williams College

Thesis: Expanding Zero-forcing to Multi-color Forcing in Graphs

2015 - 2019 Williamstown, MA

October 2023

PUBLICATIONS AND PAPERS

Hard Prompts Made Easy: Gradient-Based Discrete Optimization for Prompt Tuning and Discovery, *NeurIPS 2023* December 2023 YWen, N. Jain, J. Kirchenbauer, M. Goldblum, J. Geiping, T. Goldstein

NEFTune: Noisy Embeddings Improve Instruction Finetuning, *Under Review*

N. Jain, P. Chiang, Y. Wen, J. Kirchenbauer, H. Chu, G. Somepalli, B. Bartoldson, B. Kailkhura, A. Schwarzschild, A. Saha,

M. Goldblum, J. Geiping, T. Goldstein

Baseline Defenses for Adversarial Attacks Against Aligned Language Models, *Under Review* September 2023

N. Jain, A. Schwarzschild, Y. Wen, G. Somepalli, J. Kirchenbauer, P. Chiang, M. Goldblum, A. Saha, J. Geiping, T. Goldstein

Bring Your Own Data! Self-Supervised Evaluation for Large Language Models, *Under Review*June 2023

N Jain, K Saifullah, Y Wen, J Kirchenbauer, M Shu, A. Saha, M Goldblum, J Geiping, T Goldstein

How to Do a Vocab Swap? A Study of Embedding Replacement for Pretrained Transformers, Under Review September 2022

N Jain, J Kirchenbauer, J Geiping, T Goldstein

Multi-color Forcing in Graphs, Springer: Graphs and Combinatorics

June 2020

C Bozeman, PE Harris, N Jain, B Young, T Yu (As most math papers, authors are alphabetically order)

OTHER RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Thesis, Williams College September 2018 - May 2019
Graph Theory, Advisor Pamela Harris Williamstown, MA

Research Intern, Salk Institute For Biological Studies

May 2017 - August 2017

Computational Biology, Edward Stites Lab San Diego, CA

EMPLOYMENT

Research Assistant, University of Maryland, College Park

Professor Tom Goldstein

June 2023 - Present
College Park, MD

Teaching Assistant, University of Maryland, College Park

Advanced Numerical Optimization, Professor Tom Goldstein

January 2023 - May 2023

College Park, MD

Teaching Assistant, University of Maryland, College Park

Advanced Data Structures, Professor Micheal Marsh

September 2022 - December 2022

College Park, MD

Research Assistant, University of Maryland, College Park Professor Tom Goldstein

June 2022 - August 2022 College Park, MD

 Explored techniques on faster adaptation of existing large language models to new languages, creating new foundational models. This work is currently under review.

Teaching Assistant, University of Maryland, College Park Introduction to Data Science, Professor John Dickerson and Jose Calderon September 2021 - May 2022 College Park, MD

Summer Math Tutor, Hamilton College Consulting

June 2020 - August 2020

 Tutored students for SAT/ACT math and other broad math skills; these students saw an increase by 300 points for the SAT and 5 points on the ACT math section

Data Scientist Senior Consultant, Booz Allen Hamilton Strategic Innovation Group, Analytics

July 2020 - April 2021 Washington, DC

- Created math models such as agent-based models and simulations like Monte Carlo in python and excel for various different analyses and studies including program evaluations for DoD OSD CAPE in a research oriented approach to the problems
- Built a webapp using Flask alongside HTML, CSS, and JS to display various analyses of a curated dataset

Data Scientist Consultant, Booz Allen Hamilton Strategic Innovation Group, Analytics July 2019 - July 2020

Washington, DC

- Built an end-to-end audio analysis pipeline for an app in Dart using Tensorflow in Python
- Helped build a data pipeline from google trends to a S3 bucket that pulls every hour via a cron job for COVID-19 data lake

Summer Games Internship, Booz Allen Hamilton Strategic Innovation Group, Analytics

June 2018 - August 2018

Washington, DC

- Analyzed spatial data through QGIS's python script runner to create shapefiles for the RShiny front-end
- Used R to clean data and create a RShiny front-end

Teaching Assistant, Williams College Introduction to Mechanics, Professor William Wootters

September 2016 - December 2016

Williams College, Williamstown, MA

Internship, Anokiwave Silicon IC, Numerical Simulations July 2016 - August 2016 San Diego, CA

College Park, MD

2015-2019

RELEVANT COURSE RESEARCH PROJECTS

Studying Human Interactions with LLMs in QA Settings for Exploring Human Trust in LLMs
Course: Human-Al Interaction

Hallucinations in Closed Book Generative Question Answering
Course: How and Why Artificial Intelligence Answers Questions

Universal Adversarial Attacks on Meta-Learning Algorithms

September 2022 - December 2022 - College Park, MD

September 2022 - May 2022
College Park, MD

September 2021 - December 2021

TALKS, LEADERSHIP, AND CERTIFICATIONS

Men's Varsity Squash Team, Williams College

Course: Foundations of Deep Learning

Co-Lead Machine Learning Reading Group at UMD June 2021 Outstanding Graduate Teaching Assistant Award Recipient January 2021 Dean's and Chair's Fellowship September 2021 Moderated Panel on the Math Community for Minorities & September 2020 the Application of Math for Social Good, Williams College Quantum Algorithms for Cybersecurity, Chemistry, and Optimization Certificate, MIT xPRO April 2020 Introduction of Quantum Computing Certificate, MIT xPRO February 2020 Foundations of Natural Language Processing Certificate, NVIDIA December 2019 Foundations of Computer Vision Certificate, NVIDIA October 2019

NEEL JAIN CV PAGE 2 OF 2

SOFTWARE LANGUAGES AND TOOLS

Python; Pytorch; Transformers; Pandas; Numpy; Scikit-Learn; NLTK; Spacy; Tensorflow; Keras; Docker; Java

NEEL JAIN CV PAGE 3 OF 2